# **Andrew Cramer**

#### **OBJECTIVE STATEMENT**

I'm a Software Developer who has a focus in Game Development. After the past four years of attending Shawnee State University, I've gained a lot of experience with learning how to think critically and problem solve, write and read code to resolve problems. I also learned how to communicate effectively with others in a group setting, and understand and use many key disciplines in Computer Science. I am looking to get a start to my career in Software Development / IT, and just learn more about myself and the many thousands of things that you can do with computers.

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Gnomad (Senior Capstone Project)**

- Created a comprehensive game design document to ensure total transparency about our systems and gameplay features.
- Used OOP principles, Design Pattern techniques and focused on modularity to make expandable and maintainable code for NPC's and the Player. Also used and created a State Machine for NPC's and Player scripts to better debug systems and to make the code more maintainable.
- Created a Room Manager System to help with loading and unloading scenes asynchronously.
- Designed and thoroughly tested levels within the game to ensure that our levels were entertaining and engaging.

## **Project Dad Bod (Semester Project)**

- Created Enemy AI with Unreal's Behavior Trees in blueprints. The AI was not built very well, and because of this, I was able to look back at my downfalls towards the end of my project and understand how to better structure and create systems.
- With our group of five people, we completely over-scoped the project and fought hard to stay on track. This showed me how to properly scope a project and maintain deadlines for features and systems
- Learned how to effectively manage, access and use data structures when developing for our inventory and crafting systems.

Location:

Grove City, Ohio

Email

andrew.cramer2002@gmail.com

Portfolio:

andrewcramer3.github.io

LinkedIn:

 $\underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew}$ 

-cramer-u97

#### **SKILLS**

· C / C++ / C# · Unreal Engine

PythonCreativity

• Unity Engine • Communication

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FedEx Ground, Package Handler

MAY 2022 - FEB 2024

Cooperated with others, worked under pressure in a fast-paced environment and ensured safety in facility

#### Meijer, Cashier

MAR 2020 - JAN 2022

Communicated with people in an efficient and friendly manner

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Shawnee State University,** Portsmouth, Ohio

Bachelors in Digital Simulation and Gaming Engineering

AUG 2020 - AUG 2024

Westfall Local Schools, Williamsport, Ohio

High School Diploma

AUG 2007 - MAY 2020

#### **SCHOLARSHIPS**

Blue and Grey Scholarship